# Arun G

Mobile: +91 8095056418 / 9972258430 Email: arungangadharaiah@gmail.com

Website: www.arung.co.in

#### **SUMMARY**

Full Stack Developer with 6+ years of experience developing complex web based application and e-commerce websites. Mostly oriented towards server-side programming. Posses strong technical skills and ability to lead software development teams. Strong understanding of the internet space. Proficient in Python, Django, Ruby, Git.

# **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### Jan 2018 - Present:

Lead Engineer, Cisco Systems inc, Bangalore

Cisco is the largest networking company in the world, that develops, manufactures and sells networking hardware, telecommunications equipment and other high-technology services and products.

I'm part of AppDynamics team that contributes for Application Performance Monitoring. Mainly focusing of Performance \_improvement and Python agent development.

#### Roles and Responsibilities:

- Python agent Development and Enhancement, that would help to instrument python application.
- Customer Engagement and Monitoring complex applications.

## Oct 2016 - Dec 2017:

# Senior Software Engineer, Saltside, Bangalore

Saltside develops and operates websites in emerging markets, with focus set on online classified sites. Currently Saltside operates the top classified sites in Sri Lanka (Ikman.lk), Bangladesh (Bikroy.com) and Ghana (Tonaton.com) and Nigeria (Efritin.com). It provides platform to Buy and Sell used product online.

#### Roles and Responsibilities:

- Design and development of key features that generate revenue to the organization.
- Developing API's that serves web and mobile.
- Automating Ads review system.

# June 2014 - August 2016:

## **Senior Software Engineer**, ibibo Group, Bangalore

Goibibo is the largest online hotels booking engine in India and also one of the leading air aggregator. Goibibo is also the number one ranked mobile app under the travel category. Goibibo is part of the ibibo Group that also owns India's No. 1 online Bus ticketing platform, redBus.in.

# Roles and Responsibilities:

• Working closely with design, engineering, operations, data science, marketing and sales teams and seek their input on key product decisions.

- Develop new products/features and seek to refine existing features by conducting user research, analysing usage patterns etc.
- Manage the product development process from conception through design, development, release, analysis and iteration.
- Contributing to the overall product roadmap across all platforms (web, mobile) keeping in mind the short-term, medium-term and long-term interests of the company.
- Introducing new service that provides interface for integrating Fresh Desk as lead management, that handles auto assignment.
- Designed dynamic traveler form configuration and validation, promo code and policy.
- Developing API's that serves web and mobile.

# May 2012 - June 2014:

Software Engineer, Mango Games Interactive Private Limited, Bangalore

Mango Games is a developer of social, multiplayer turn-based and real-time games for Web and mobile devices. Social Rummy, Social Mobsters (Don) and Mumbai Mobsters are popular titles developed by Mango Games.

### Roles and Responsibilities:

- Developed a game analytics and reporting solution on MongoDB and Ruby on Rails under the guidance of a senior engineer. Eventually took over the ownership of the application and its enhancements.
- Developed an optimised leader-board solution as a Ruby backend job, with automated daily update of leader-board HTML to Amazon S3 node.
- Developed a MongoDB based solution for storing and retrieving users social graph. This solution was built on Java, as a plugin to a SmartFox-2x gaming server.

## OTHER HEIGHTS OF LIFE AND EXPERIENCES

## Co-Founder, Dozoff

Dozoff is a community for fun which is open for all. With the intention to make everyone laugh everyday, we have taken the first step to create a platform where anyone can share their funny images or memes with the entire world. With that said, no more closed groups and no more feeling lonely as Dozoff is your "Stress buster".

Dozoff is developed using Python and Django.

#### TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: Python, Ruby, C++, C

Web Development: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, JQuery

Frameworks: Django, Rails Database: MySQL, MongoDB

Memory Management: Memcache, Redis

Specialties: Git, Agile Software Development, SEO, Information Management, Team Building, Leadership.

### **EDUCATION**

Completed Bachelor of Engineering (BE) in Computer Science from Siddaganga Institute of Technology (SIT), One of the top most Engineering Colleges in State of Karnataka affiliated under Visweshwaraiah Technological University (VTU) with aggregate of **8.85** GPA.